payable.com 2017-05-14

# Privacy Policy

Last Updated: January 1, 2016

### What this Privacy Policy Covers

This policy covers how Tiempo Labs, Inc., a Delaware corporation ( **" **Tiempo Labs** ,"** **“Tiempo,”** **“Payable”** , **"we,"** **"us,"** or **"our"** ) treats personal and company information that it collects and receives on [www.payable.com](http://www.payable.com/), including all subpages and successor pages (collectively referred to as the **“Website”** ), and also applies to all software (the **“Payable Software”** ) and services that we offer through our Website (collectively referred to as the “Tiempo Labs Service”).

This Privacy Policy is incorporated into, and considered a part of, the Tiempo Labs Terms and Conditions, currently located at www.payable.com/terms. Any terms not defined herein have the meanings ascribed to them in the Terms and Conditions.

### 1\. USER Consent

By submitting or making available Derived Data or Personal Data (as defined below) through our Website, the Payable Software or the Tiempo Labs Service, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and you expressly consent to the processing of your Derived Data and Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Your Personal Data may be processed in the country in which it was collected and in other countries, including the United States, where laws regarding processing of Personal Data may be less stringent than the laws in your country.

### 2\. A Note About Children

Our Website, the Payable Software and the Tiempo Labs Service are directed to the general public. We do not knowingly collect information from children under 13 years of age or have any reasonable grounds for believing that children under the age of 13 are accessing our Website or using the Tiempo Lab Service. If we learn that we have inadvertently collected Personal Data from a child under age 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from a child under age 13, please contact us at [privacy@payable.com](mailto:privacy@payable.com?subject=Child%20Under%20Age%2013).

### 3\. Types of PErsonal Data We Collect

Tiempo Labs collects Personal Data and Anonymous Data from you when you visit our site, when you send us information or communications in connection with your use of the Tiempo Labs Service, when you register for the Tiempo Labs Service, and/or when you download and use the Payable Software.  **“Personal Data”**  means data that allows someone to identify or contact you, including, for example, your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, as well as any other non-public information about you that is associated with or linked to any of the foregoing data.  **“Anonymous Data”**  means data about you that is not associated with or linked to your Personal Data (but does not include Derived Data, which is addressed below); Anonymous Data does not permit the identification of individual persons. We collect Personal Data and Anonymous Data, as described below.

 **Personal Data You Provide to Us**  
We collect Personal Data from you, such as first and last name, e-mail and mailing addresses, country, telephone number, W-9 information, tax identification number (e.g., social security number or employer identification number), birth date, professional title, company name, legal entity type, bank account information and password, when you register for the Tiempo Labs Service. In order to receive payment, Contractors must provide to Payable their legal name, legal entity type, tax identification number (e.g., social security number or employer identification number), date of birth or date of formation, physical address, country, bank account number, and bank routing number. In addition, we (or our third-party credit card or payment processor on our behalf) will collect Personal Data including your credit card number or account information when you upgrade to a paid account. We also retain information on your behalf, such as the Personal Data described above and any correspondence. If you provide us feedback or contact us via e-mail (e.g., in response to a survey about Payable or writing support to ask a question), we will collect your name and e-mail address, as well as any other content included in the e-mail, in order to send you a reply, and any information that you submit to us, such as a resume. If we conduct a survey in which you participate, we may collect additional profile information. We also collect other types of Personal Data that you provide to us voluntarily and other requested information if you contact us via e-mail regarding support for the Tiempo Labs Service. We may also collect Personal Data at other points in our website that state that Personal Data is being collected. 

Should you register for a Tiempo Labs subscription account, we require your billing information in order to process the transaction. We will retain the last 4 digits of your credit card number and credit card type, so that you may identify that card used in the future.  A recurring subscription will be created at our payment gateway, which will store your billing information for as long as necessary to carry out the terms of your subscription. Should you cancel your subscription, your billing information will be promptly removed by our payment gateway.

 **Personal Data Collected by Third Parties**  
We may receive Personal Data about you from other sources like telephone or fax, from companies that distribute the Tiempo Labs Service by way of a co-branded or private-labeled website, companies that offer their products and/or services via the Tiempo Labs Service, or companies that provide services (such as payment processing services) in connection with the Tiempo Labs Service (collectively,  **“Partner Companies”** ). Our Partner Companies may supply us with Personal Data, such as your name and e-mail and mailing address information, in order to help us establish the account or fulfill orders. We may add this information to the information we have already collected from you via our website in order to perform and improve the Tiempo Labs Service.

This Privacy Policy applies only to the use and disclosure of Personal Data that we collect while you use the Tiempo Labs Service. Our provision of a link to any other website or location is for your convenience and does not signify our endorsement of such other website or location or its contents. When you click on such a link, you will leave our site and go to another site. During this process, a third party may collect Personal Data or Anonymous Data from you.

 **Personal Data Collected via Technology**  
The Tiempo Labs Service (which may be hosted by a third-party service provider) collects Personal Data from you, such as browser type, operating system, Internet Protocol (IP) address, domain name, and/or a date/time stamp for your visit. We may also use Cookies (as defined below) and navigational data like Uniform Resource Locators (URL) to gather information regarding the date and time of your visit and/or access to the Tiempo Labs Service and the solutions and information for which you searched and which you viewed. Like most Internet services, we automatically gather this Personal Data and store it in log files each time you visit our website or access your account. We also collect other use information as part of our analytics services, in order to improve the Tiempo Labs Service.

 **“Cookies”**  are small pieces of information that a website sends to your computer’s hard drive while you are viewing a web site. We may use both session Cookies (which expire once you close your web browser) and persistent Cookies (which stay on your computer until you delete them) to provide you with a more personal and interactive experience while using the Tiempo Labs Service. Persistent Cookies can be removed by following Internet browser help file directions. If you choose to disable Cookies, some areas of our website and/or the Tiempo Labs Service may not function correctly.

We have no control over, do not review, and cannot be responsible for, these outside websites or their content. Please be aware that the terms of this Privacy Policy do not apply to these outside websites or content, or to any collection of data after you click on a link to a third party.

 **Do Not Track**  
While we are committed to your privacy, currently, the Tiempo Labs Service does not respond to your web browser “do not track” signals or other mechanisms.  If, in the future, we create a program or protocol to respond to such web browser “do not track” signals, we will inform you of the details of that protocol in this Privacy Policy.

### 4\. Use of Your Personal Data

Tiempo Labs uses your Personal Data in the following ways:

  * To facilitate the creation of and secure your account; identify and authenticate you as a user in our system
  * To provide improved administration of the Tiempo Labs Service
  * To improve the quality of experience when you interact with the Tiempo Labs Service
  * To send you a welcome e-mail to verify ownership of the e-mail address provided when your account was created
  * To send you administrative e-mail notifications, such as security or support and maintenance advisories
  * To respond to your inquiries related to employment opportunities or other requests
  * To send promotional communications
  * To provide you with hardcopy or electronic newsletters, or surveys
  * To send upgrades and special offers related to the Tiempo Labs Service and for other marketing purposes of Tiempo Labs or our Partner Companies, should you request to receive such communications from us
  * To make telephone calls to you, from time to time, as a part of secondary fraud protection or to solicit your feedback

We may create Anonymous Data records from Personal Data by excluding information (such as your name) that render the data personally identifiable to you. We use this Anonymous Data to enhance the content and functionality of the Tiempo Labs Service. Tiempo Labs reserves the right to use Anonymous Data for other purposes and to disclose Anonymous Data to third parties in its discretion.

If you provide feedback on the Tiempo Labs Service, we may use such feedback for any purpose, provided we will not associate such feedback with your Derived Data or your Personal Data. Tiempo Labs will collect any information contained in such communication and will treat the Derived Data and Personal Data in such communication in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### 5\. Disclosure of Your Personal Data

We may allow you to store your W-9 information and share such W-9 information with entities to which you provide services through Payable.

We may share your Personal Data with Partner Companies to provide technical support or to provide specific services, such as hosting of your applications, maintenance services, database management, or payment processing for purchases. Partner Companies will have access to your Personal Data only to perform these services on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose. Partner Companies agree in writing to provide the same or greater level of privacy protection as required by Tiempo Labs.

Although we currently do not have a parent company, any subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under a common control (collectively,  **“Related Entities”** ), we may in the future. We may share some or all of your Personal Data with these Related Entities, in which case we will require our Related Entities to honor this Privacy Policy. If another company acquires our company or our assets, that company will possess the Personal Data collected by it and us and will assume the rights and obligations regarding your Personal Data as described in this Privacy Policy. 

Regardless of any choices you make regarding your Personal Data (as described below), Tiempo Labs may disclose Personal Data if it believes in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to (a) comply with relevant laws or to respond to subpoenas or warrants served on Tiempo Labs; (b) protect or defend the rights or property of Tiempo Labs or users of the Tiempo Labs Service; or (c) protect the safety of the public or any person, or to prevent or stop any activity we may consider to be, or to pose a risk of being, illegal, unethical or legally actionable. 

Except as otherwise stated in this policy, we do not generally sell, trade, share, or rent the Personal Data collected from our services to third parties. You expressly consent to the sharing of your Personal Data as described in this policy.

### 6\. Opt Out Policy and Personal Data Changes

We offer you choices regarding the collection, use, and sharing of your Personal Data. We may periodically send you newsletters and e-mails that directly promote the use of the Tiempo Labs Service and may contain advertisements for third parties. When you receive newsletters or promotional communications from us, you may indicate a preference to stop receiving further communications from us and you will have the opportunity to “opt-out” by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in the e-mail you receive or by contacting us directly (please see contact information below). Should you decide to opt-out of receiving future mailings, we may share your e-mail address with third parties to ensure that you do not receive further communications from third parties. Despite your indicated e-mail preferences, we may send you notice of any updates to our Terms and Conditions or Privacy Policy.

You may access and change any of your Personal Data in your account by editing your profile within the registration portion of our website or by sending an e-mail to our Customer Support at [support@payable.com](mailto:support@payable.com). You may request deletion of your account information by us, but please note that we may be required (by law or otherwise) to keep this information and not delete it (or to keep this information for a certain time, in which case we will comply with your deletion request only after we have fulfilled such requirements). When we delete account information, it will be deleted from the active database, but may remain in our archives.

### 7\. Types of Derived Data We Collect

Tiempo Labs collects Derived Data when you use the Tiempo Labs Service. “Derived Data” means data about the performance of the Tiempo Labs Service, applications, system data (names of plug-ins, etc.), data about transactions taking place and other similar data related to the performance of the Tiempo Labs Service.

### 8\. Use of Your Derived Data

Derived Data we collect is primarily used to display performance information back to the User. It is also used by Tiempo Labs personnel to answer questions that Users may have about their account and to develop and improve our products. Tiempo Labs may also aggregate Derived Data across multiple accounts and use this data to create and publish industry benchmarks or comparative application performance metrics.

### 9\. Disclosure of Your Derived Data

We may share your Derived Data with Partner Companies to provide technical support or to provide specific services, such as hosting of your applications, maintenance services, database management or payment processing for purchases.

Partner Companies will have access to your Derived Data only to perform these services on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose. 

Tiempo Labs may disclose Derived Data if it believes in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to (a) comply with relevant laws or to respond to subpoenas or warrants served on Tiempo Labs; or (b) protect or defend the rights or property of Tiempo Labs or users of the Tiempo Labs Service. 

We may share some or all of your Derived Data with Related Entities, in which case we will require our Related Entities to honor this Privacy Policy. If another company acquires our company or our assets, that company will possess the Derived Data collected by it and us and will assume the rights and obligations regarding your Derived Data as described in this Privacy Policy. 

Except as otherwise stated in this policy, we do not generally disclose the Derived Data collected from the Tiempo Labs Service to third parties without consent from you. You expressly consent to the sharing of your Derived Data as described in this policy.

### 10\. California Privacy Rights

Our Users who are California residents may request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, certain information about the Personal Data (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year. If applicable, this information would include a list of the categories of Personal Data that was shared and the names and addresses of all third parties with which we shared information in the immediately preceding calendar year. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request in writing to [privacy@payable.com](mailto:privacy@payable.com?subject=California%20Privacy%20Rights).

### 11\. Security of Your Application and Personal Data

Tiempo Labs is committed to protecting the security of your Derived Data and Personal Data. We use a variety of industry-standard security technologies and procedures to help protect your Derived Data and Personal Data from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. We also require you to enter a password to access your account information. Your account's password is stored using a randomly salted, one-way hash algorithm. Please do not disclose your account password to unauthorized people. Despite these measures, you should know that Tiempo Labs cannot fully eliminate security risks associated with Derived Data and Personal Data and mistakes and security breaches may happen. Tiempo Labs uses industry-standard SSL-encryption to protect data transmissions. However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed by breach of such firewalls and secure server software.

If Tiempo Labs learns of a security systems breach we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. By using the Service or providing personal information to us, you agree that we can communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy and administrative issues relating to your use of those sites, products and services. We may post a notice on our applicable Websites if a security breach occurs. If this happens, you will need a web browser enabling you to view the applicable Websites. We may also send an email to you at the email address you have provided to us in these circumstances. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing. To receive free written notice of a security breach (or to withdraw your consent from receiving electronic notice) you should notify us at [privacy@payable.com](mailto:privacy@payable.com).

### 12\. Privacy

Tiempo Labs personnel undergo rigorous hiring processes. All employees are bound by a confidentiality agreement that covers the protection of all customer information.

### 13 Contact Information

Tiempo Labs welcomes your comments or questions regarding this Privacy Policy. Feel free to e-mail comments or questions to us at [privacy@payable.com](mailto:privacy@tiempolabs.com) or write to: 

Tiempo Labs, Inc.   
73 Sumner St. #302   
San Francisco, CA 94103

### 14\. Changes to this Privacy Policy

If Tiempo Labs makes changes to this Privacy Policy, these changes will be posted on our website in a timely manner. Tiempo Labs reserves the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently. You can determine when this Privacy Policy was last revised by referring to the “Last Updated” legend at the top of this page. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will become effective upon our posting of the revised Privacy Policy on the Site. Use of the Tiempo Labs Service following such changes constitutes your acceptance of the revised Privacy Policy then in effect.
